

Quick-learner. Problem-solver.

utkarshgaur.com +1 416-371-9661 utkarshgaur07@gmail.com 3040 Knob Hill, Mississauga, Ontario

Computer Engineer with 5+ years of field experience. I have spent the past three years shifting my focus from networking hardware to software development. I'm now seeking an opportunity to bring my computer engineering experience to an agile-oriented team.

### **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelor of Applied Science and Engineering (BASc)**

May 2013

Engineering Science, Major in Electrical and Computer Engineering University of Toronto, St. George Campus

### **SKILLS**

**Programming Languages** C#, JavaScript, C++, HMTL, CSS, Java

**Applications** Unity3D, MonoDevelop, VSCode

Second Languages French, Hindi

### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

Game Developer Mar 2015 – Present

Self-Employed, Mississauga, Ontario

Developed multiple games using C# and Unity3D Editor

- Removed code-fragility using Test-Driven Development (TDD) via NUnit
- Coded enemy pathing, social simulation, card game mechanics
- Built website using HTML5 / CSS / JS to showcase games

#### **Applications Engineer**

Nov 2013 - Dec 2014

Calnex Solutions, Linlithgow, Scotland and Ottawa, Ontario

- · Designed lab test environments around the Attero product line
- Troubleshot customer issues
- · Directed feature development

## **Applications Architect**

May 2010 - Jun 2011

Bell Canada, Toronto, Ontario

- Automated Quality Assurance (QA) using Tcl and AutoIT
- Performed QA on and debugged Routing Gateways (RG) for the internet, working with multiple teams
- Proposed and developed a bug tracking solution with real-time backups

# **PERSONAL SKILLS AND HOBBIES**

Public Speaking Advanced Communicator Silver Award (Oct 2013) from Toastmasters
President "University of Toronto Engineering Toastmasters" club (2010-2011)
Hobbies Writing short stories, biking along trails, playing video-games

**References Available Upon Request**